# AKINBOLA **LAIDE-ABUDU**

### FRONT-END DEVELOPER

+234 808 342 4584 akinbolaabudu@gmail.com in /akinabudu





/akinabudu

#### PROFILE

As a front-end web developer with a Computer and Information Science degree, I have over five years of experience in creating web and mobile applications. I am proficient in using tools such as React and Figma, and I have a keen eye for details. I also possess strong creative and analytical skills that help me deliver quality work.

## SKILLS

- Responsive Design
- Collaboration
- API Integration
- Testing and Debugging
- Version Control
- Problem Solving

#### TECH STACK

Javascript, React, ReactNative, Svelte, Next.js, Node.js, Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, MongoDB, Python, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Git, Linux, SQL, Appwrite, Postgres, REST API, Docker, AWS.

## EDUCATION

**BACHELOR OF SCIENCE** 

Lead City University, Ibadan 2006 - 2010

# EXPERIENCE

# FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

ORGLOBAL TECH NETWORK LTD.

2020 - Present

- One of my proudest achievements was leading the development of a complex web application for a client that required integration with multiple third-party APIs.
- I have implemented several performance optimizations and scalability measures that have helped to improve the overall user experience of web applications.

#### SENIOR FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER NIMBUS-AI LLC 2023- Present

- Developed the NIMBUS Cybersecurity Academy software that enables the students to take courses, exams and access test labs.
- Developed and maintained web applications using modern technologies, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and various frameworks such as NextJs and Tailwind.
- Integrated RESTful APIs and backend services to create interactive and dynamic web applications

#### CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner- AWS
- Responsive Web Design- FreeCodeCamp
- Python for Absolute Beginner -EC-Council
- Introduction to HTML5 Cousera
- Introduction to Cybersecurity CISCO